Hello everyone, welcome back.
大家好 欢迎回来
So in this network, we will be using a pre-trained network to solve
在这个网络中 我们将使用预训练网络
this challenging problem of creating a classifier for your cat and dog images.
解决创建猫狗图像分类器的难题
These pre-trained networks were trained on ImageNet which is
这些预训练网络是在 ImageNet 上训练的
a massive dataset of over one million labeled images from 1,000 different categories.
ImageNet 是一个大型数据集 包含超过一百万张有标记图像 具有 1000 种不同类别
These are available from torchvision and this module, torchvision.models.
可以从 torchvision 的 torchvision.models 模型中获取这些图像
And so, we see we have six different architectures that we can use,
可以使用的架构有六种
and here's a nice breakdown of the performance of each of these different models.
这是每个模型的性能的细分表
So, AlexNet gives us the top one error and the top five error.
AlexNet 显示 top-1 错误率和 top-5 错误率
So basically, as you see,
可以看出
some of these networks and these numbers here,
在这些网络中 这些数字
19, 11, 34, and so on,
19 11 34 等等
they usually indicate the number of layers in this model.
通常表示的是模型中的层数
So, the larger this number,
数字越大
the larger the model is.
模型越大
you get better accuracy,
准确度越高
you get lower errors.
错误率越低
At the same time,
同时
again, the larger the model is,
模型越大
the longer it's going to take to compute your predictions and to train and all that.
计算预测值和训练所需的时间越长
So when you're using these,
所以 使用这些模型时
you need to think about the tradeoff between accuracy and speed.
需要在准确度和速度之间权衡
So, all these networks use an architecture called convolutional layers.
所有这些网络使用的架构称为卷积层
What these do, they exploit patterns and regularities in images.
卷积层会挖掘图像中的图案和规则性
I'm not going to get into the details but if you want to learn more about them,
这里不做详细讲解 想要了解更多
you can watch this video.
可以观看这个视频
So we're saying, these deep learning networks are typically very deep.
这些深度学习网络一般非常深
So that means, they have dozens or even hundreds of different layers,
换句话说 它们有几十个甚至几百个层
and they were trained on this massive ImageNet dataset.
并且在 ImageNet 大型数据集中对其进行了训练
It turns out that they were astonishingly well
我们发现 对于未训练过的图像
as future detectors for images that they weren't trained on.
它们检测特征的效果非常好
So using a pre-trained network like this on
对未见过的训练集使用
a training set that it hasn't seen before is called transfer learning.
这种预训练网络 称为迁移学习
So basically, what's learned from
在 ImageNet 数据集中学习的东西
the ImageNet dataset is being transferred to your dataset.
都会迁移到你的数据集中
So here, we're going to use transfer learning to train
我们将利用迁移学习训练自己的网络
our own network to classify our cat and dog photos.
从而对猫狗图像进行分类
What you'll see is you'll get really good performance with very little work on our side.
你会发现 我们需要做的很少 但是性能非常好
So again, you can download these models from torchvision.models,
可以从 torchvision.models 模型中下载这些模型
this model here, so we can include this in our imports, right here.
将其添加到这里的导入内容中
Most of these pre-trained models require a 224 by 224 image as the input.
大多数预训练模型需要 224*224 的图像作为输入
You'll also need to match a normalization
在 ImageNet 上训练这些模型时
used when these models were trained on ImageNet.
还需要匹配所使用的归一化函数
So when they train these models,
所以 训练这些模型时
each color channel and images were normalized separately.
每个颜色通道和图像都会单独归一化
And you can see the means here and the standard deviations here.
这些是均值 这些是标准偏差
So, I'm going to leave it up to you to define
现在请你定义训练数据和
the transformations for the training data and the testing data now.
测试数据的转换
And if you're done, we can get to a new one.
完成之后 可以进行下一个单元
Now, let's see how we can actually load in one of these models.
我们现在看一下 如何加载模型
So here, I'm going to use the Densenet-121 model.
我将使用 Densenet-121 模型
So you see, it has very high accuracy on
它对 ImageNet 数据集的准确度非常高
the ImageNet dataset and it's one 121 tells us that it has 121 layers.
121 表示它有 121 层
To load this in our code and use it,
为了把它加载到代码中并使用
so we just say model models.densenet121 and then we say pretrained equals true.
输入 model = models.densenet121(pretrained=True)
So this is going to download the pre-trained network,
将会下载预训练网络
the weights, the parameters themselves,
权重 参数本身
and then load it into our model.
然后加载到模型中
So now, we can do that and then we can look at what the architecture of this model.
现在可以看一下模型的架构
And this is what our DenseNet architecture looks like.
这就是 DenseNet 架构
So, you'll notice that we have this features part here and then a bunch of these layer.
你会发现这里有个特征部分 还有多个层
So this is like a convolutional layer which again I'm not going to talk about
这是卷积层 这里不做讲解
here but you don't really need to understand it to be able to actually use this thing.
即使不理解也可以使用
There's two main parts that we're interested in.
我们感兴趣的主要有两个部分
So firstly, again, this features part,
第一个是特征部分
but then if we scroll all the way to the bottom,
一直拉到底
we also see this classifier part.
可以看到分类器部分
So we see here is that we have the classifier.
这里可以看到分类器
This has been defined as a linear combination layer,
它被定义为线性组合层
it's a fully connected dense layer,
是一个全连接密集层
and it has 1,024 input features and then 1,000 output features.
有 1024 个输入特征 1000 个输出特征
So again, the ImageNet dataset has 1,000 different classes.
所以 ImageNet 数据集有 1000 个不同类
And so, the the number of outputs of
这个网络的输出数量
this network should be 1,000 for each of those classes.
应该是每个类 1000 个
So, the thing to know is that this whole thing was trained on ImageNet.
要注意的是 整个网络是在 ImageNet 上训练的
Now, the features will work for
特征对其它数据集也适用
other datasets but the classifier itself has been trained for ImageNet.
但分类器本身是针对 ImageNet 训练的
So this is the part that we need to retrain, the classifier.
所以 分类器需要重新训练
We want to keep the feature part static.
我们想让特征部分保持不变
We don't want to update that,
不更新
but we just need to update the classifier part.
但需要更新分类器部分
So then, the first thing we need to do is freeze our feature parameters.
首先需要冻结特征参数
To do that, we go through our parameters in our model.
遍历模型中的参数
And then, we just say, requires_grad equals false.
然后输入 requires_grad = False
So what this will do is that when we run our tensors through the model,
这样 在模型中运行张量时
it's not going to calculate the gradients.
不会计算梯度
It's not going to keep track of all these operations.
不会跟踪所有运算
So firstly, this is going to ensure that
这是为了确保
our our feature parameters don't get updated but it
特征参数不被更新
also will speed up training because
同时加快训练速度
we're not keeping track of these operations for the features.
因为没有跟踪特征的运算
Now, we need to replace the classifier with our own classifier.
现在需要把这个分类器替换成我们自己的分类器
So here, I'm going to use a couple of new things.
我将使用几个新东西
I'm going to use the sequential module available from PyTorch.
我将使用 sequential 模型 它可以从 PyTorch 中获取
And so, what this does, you basically just give it
给它提供一个你想进行的
a list of different operations you want to
运算列表
do and then it will automatically pass a tensor through them sequentially.
它会自动依次传入张量
So, you can pass in an ordered dict to name each of these layers.
可以传入一个有序字典 对每个层进行命名
So I'll show you how this works.
我将演示如何操作
So we want a fully connected layer,
需要一个全连接层
so I'll just name it FC1,
将其命名为 FC1
and then that is a fully connected layer coming from
这个全连接层
1,024 inputs and I'm going to say 500 for this hidden layer.
有 1024 个输入 隐藏层有 500 个输入
And then we want to pass this through ReLu activation and
然后进行 ReLu 激活
then this should go through
然后前往
another fully connected layer and this will be our output layer.
另一个全连接层 即输出层
So, 500 to two,
500, 2
so we have cat and dog,
我们有猫和狗的图像
so we want two outputs here.
所以有两个输出
And finally, our output is going to be the LogSoftmax like before.
最后的输出是 LogSoftmax 和之前一样
Okay, and that is how we define the classifier.
这就是分类器的定义步骤
So now, we can take this classifier,
现在可以将
just a classifier built from fully connected layers,
用全连接层构建的分类器
and we can attach it to our model.classifier.
附加到 model.classifier 中
So now, the new classifier that we built that is
现在 构建的未训练的新分类器
untrained is attached to our model and this model also has the features parts.
已附加到模型中 这个模型也具有特征部分
The features parts are going to remain frozen.
特征部分将保持不变
We're not going to update those weights but we need to train our new classifier.
我们不会更新权重 但需要训练新的分类器
Now, if we want to train our network that we're using,
如果想要训练正在使用的网络
this Densenet-121 is really deep and it has 121 layers.
Densenet-121 非常深 有 121 个层
So, if we can try to train this on the CPU like normal,
如果尝试在普通 CPU 上训练
it's going to take pretty much forever.
将要花费很长时间
So instead, what we can do is use the GPU.
所以可以使用 GPU
GPUs are built specifically for doing a bunch of linear algebra computations in
GPU 是为了同时进行多个线性代数计算而专门构建的
parallel and our neural networks are
神经网络一般是
basically just a bunch of linear algebra computations.
由多个线性代数计算组成
So if we run these on the GPU,
在 GPU 上
they're done in parallel and we get something like 100 times increase speeds.
这些计算会同时进行 速度会提高 100 倍
In PyTorch, it's pretty straightforward to use the GPU.
在 PyTorch 中 GPU 的使用非常简单
If you have your model, so model,
如果有模型
the idea is that your model has all these parameters in there
模型的所有参数都是张量的形式
tensors that are sitting in your memory on your computer,
位于计算机的内存中
but we can move them over to our GPU by saying model.cuda.
但可以通过 model.cuda 将其移动到 GPU 中
So what this does is it moves the parameters for your model to the GPU
这样就把模型的参数移动到 GPU 中
and then all of the computations and the processing and are going to be done on the GPU.
所有的计算和处理都会在 GPU 中完成
Similarly, if you have a tensor like your images, select images,
同样 如果有张量 例如 图像
if you want to run your images through your model,
如果想在模型中运行图像
you have to make sure that the tensors that you're putting
如果模型在 GPU 中
through your model or on the GPU if your model's on the GPU.
必须确保模型中的张量也在 GPU 中
So you just have to make those match up.
必须将其匹配起来
So to do that, to move a tensor from computer to the GPU,
如需将张量从计算机移动到 GPU
you just, again, say images.cuda.
可以使用 images.cuda
So that will move a tensor,
这可以将张量
that's images, to the GPU.
也就是图像 移动到 GPU
Then oftentimes, you'll want to move your model and your tensors back
我们经常需要把模型的张量
from the GPU to your local memory and CPU, and so, to do that,
从 GPU 移回本地内存和 CPU
you just say like model.cpu or images.cpu,
可以使用 model.cpu 或 images.cpu
so this'll bring your tensors
这样就将张量
back from the GPU to your local computer to run on your CPU.
从 GPU 移回本地计算机 从而在 CPU 上运行
Now, I'm going to give you a demonstration of how this all works
现在我将演示如何进行这个过程
and the amazing increased speed we get by using the GPU.
以及 GPU 对速度有多大的提升
So here, I'm just going to do for cuda and false, true.
执行 for cuda in [False, True]
So this way, I'm going to be able to basically like loop
这样就能在不使用 GPU
through and try it once where we're not using the GPU,
的情况和使用 GPU 的
and once where we are using the GPU.
情况之间循环
So let's define my criterion which is going to be
像平常一样 将条件定义为
natural log_loss like we'd normally do, define our optimizer.
nn.NLLLoss 然后定义优化器
So again, here, remember that we only want to update the parameters for the classifier.
记住 我们只想更新分类器的参数
So we're just going to pass in model.classifier.parameters.
所以只传入 model.classifier.parameters
This will work and that it's going to update the premise for our classifier but
这样将会更新分类器的参数
it's going to lead the parameters for the feature detector part of the model static.
但模型特征检测器部分的参数保持不变
So I typically do is, say like, if cuda,
输入 if cuda
then we want to move our model to the GPU.
将模型移动到 GPU
Otherwise, let's leave it on the CPU.
否则将其保留在 CPU
And then I'm going to write a little training loop.
然后编写一个简短的训练循环
We'll get our inputs and our labels,
像平常一样 将输入和标签
changes into variables like normal, then again,
转换成变量
if we have cuda enabled,
如果启用了 cuda
so if we have GPUs,
如果有 GPU
then we can do inputs, labels,
那么可以将输入 标签
and we'll just move these over to the GPU.
移动到 GPU
We're using the GPU now and we're also using this pre-trained network, but in general,
我们使用了 GPU 也使用了预训练网络
you're going to do the training loop exactly the same way
但是一般来说 训练循环应该和
you have been doing it with these feed forward networks that you've been building.
你建立的前馈网络中使用的完全相同
So first, I'm actually going to define a start time just so I can time things,
首先 定义一个起始时间 便于计时
then you just do your training pass like normal.
然后像平常一样进行训练时的完整遍历
So, you just do a forward pass through your model and you can calculate the loss,
在模型中进行前向传播遍历 然后计算损失
do your backward pass.
进行反向传播遍历
Finally, update your weights with your optimizer.
最后 更新优化器的权重
So I'm going to do here, I'm going to break
在前三次迭代之后
this training loop after the first three iterations.
我现在将中断这个训练循环
So I want to time the difference between using a GPU and not using the GPU.
我想对使用 GPU 和不使用 GPU 的两种情况之间的差别进行计时
What happens is the very first batch to go
结果表明 训练循环中的
through the training loop tends to take longer than the other batches,
第一批花费的时间多于其它批
so I'm just going to take the first three or four and then average over those
所以取前三批或前四批 取其平均值
just so we get a better sense of how long it actually takes to process one batch.
以便更好分析处理一批实际所花费的时间
So, that will just print out our training times.
这一步会打印出训练次数
So we can see that if we're not using the GPU,
可以看出 如果不使用 GPU
then each batch takes five and a half seconds to actually go through this training step.
每批进行训练步骤实际花费的时间是五秒半
Whereas, with the GPU,
但在使用 GPU 时
it only takes 0.012 seconds.
只需 0.012 秒
So, I mean, this is a speedup of over 100 times.
这意味着速度提升了 100 倍以上
So here, I basically set cuda manually but you can also check
我是手动设置 cuda 的 你也可以检查
if a GPU is available so you say torch.cuda is available,
GPU 是否可用 输入 torch.cuda.is_available
and this will give you back true or false depending if you have
根据是否有可以使用 cuda 的 GPU
a GPU available that can use cuda.
将会返回“真”或“假”
Okay, so from here,
从现在开始
I'm going to let you finish training this model.
请你完成这个模型的训练
So you can either continue with a DenseNet model that is already
可以继续使用已经加载的 DenseNet 模型
loaded or you can try ResNet which is also a good model to try out.
也可以尝试 ResNet
I also really like VGGNet,
我也喜欢用 VGGNet
I think that one's pretty good.
这个也很不错
It's really up to you. Cheers.
具体由你决定 谢谢